<?xml-model href="https://etc.princeton.edu/abcbooks/schema/abcbooks.schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:tei="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
   xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Laugh and Learn ABC</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Princeton University</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Princeton, New Jersey</pubPlace>
            <idno type="voyagerid">4976202</idno>
            <idno type="abcbooksid">4976202-laugh-learn</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblStruct>
               <monogr>
                  <title level="m">
                     <seg type="main">Laugh and learn ABC book</seg>
                  </title>
                  <imprint>
                     <pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
                     <publisher>McLoughlin Bros. Inc.</publisher>
                     <date notBefore="1900">c1900 1900</date>
                  </imprint>
               </monogr>
            </biblStruct>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>

   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
      <surface xml:id="page_image1">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000001.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image2">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000002.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image3">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000003.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image4">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000004.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image5">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000005.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image6">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000006.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image7">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000007.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image8">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000008.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image9">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000009.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image10">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000010.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image11">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000011.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image12">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000012.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image13">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000013.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image14">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000014.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image15">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000015.jp2"/>
      </surface>
      <surface xml:id="page_image16">
         <graphic ana="lowres" mimeType="image/jp2" url="00000016.jp2"/>
      </surface>
   </facsimile>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <pb n="1" facs="page_image1"/>
            <div>
               <ab><lb/>LAUGH AND LEARN <lb/>ABC BOOK </ab>
            </div>
            <pb n="2" facs="page_image2"/>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag1" ana="A">
               <head>A</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>An Ape and Ass, who took a walk in company, one day</l>
                  <l>Were startled by an Adder, that rose hissing in their way:</l>
                  <l>"Of course, of such a creature," cried the Ape, "I have no fear;</l>
                  <l>But it makes me somewhat nervous, and I'd rather not go near."</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag2" ana="B">
               <head>B</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>"A THING they call by your name, I observe the ladies wear,</l>
                  <l>Around their necks in this way," to the Boa said the Bear.</l>
                  <l>"Now, if you'll let me wear you," he continued, with a smile,</l>
                  <l>I'll take it as a favor, for I love to be in style."</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag3" ana="C">
               <head>C</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>"IT is not grief that makes me weep," a crocodile replied,</l>
                  <l>To a Camel, who, with kindly words to ease his sorrow tried.</l>
                  <l>"We Crocodiles are famous for our tears, my friend, you know,</l>
                  <l>So, just for practice, every day, I let a gallon flow."</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <pb n="3" facs="page_image3"/>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag4" ana="D">
               <head>D</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>THIS Duckling is his loving parents' treasure and their pride;</l>
                  <l>He has a Bow-wow Nursie, that takes him out to ride;</l>
                  <l>And the darling, in his carriage, looks so pretty and so sweet,</l>
                  <l>He's gushed o'er by all lady Ducks the road they meet.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag5" ana="E">
               <head>E</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>AN Elephant went fishing, once, but though he fished with zeal,</l>
                  <l>He didn't catch a single thing, except a slippery Eel.</l>
                  <l>It tried to squirm away from him, - " No use, dear boy!" he cried;</l>
                  <l>"I can not bear to part with you; I dearly love Eels - fried!"</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag6" ana="F">
               <head>F</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>A FROG that met a Fox, one morning, walking on the shore ;</l>
                  <l>Cried, " Foxy, why, I never knew you cared for Fish, before!"</l>
                  <l>"Well, Froggy, Geese are scarce just now," the Fox said, with a grin, </l>
                  <l>"And if I don't eat something, I'm afraid I'll get too thin."</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <pb n="4" facs="page_image4"/>
            <div>
               <lg>
                  <l>FOR the game of Croquet, Tommy Purr didn't care</l>
                  <l>Till he met Kitty Mouser, so sweet and so fair.</l>
                  <l>Now he plays it with her almost every fine day -</l>
                  <l>There will soon be a wedding, the gossips all say !</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div>
               <lg>
                  <l>MRS. GOAT must go shopping, and leave by themselves</l>
                  <l>Her dear little Kids, seven playful young elves.</l>
                  <l>She bids them be careful, and sharply look out</l>
                  <l>For a sly wicked Wolf, that is prowling about;</l>
                  <l>They must keep the door fastened, and not let him in,</l>
                  <l>Or quickly he'd eat them, bones, body, and skin !</l>
                  <l>Let us hope that the Kids will their mother obey,</l>
                  <l>And that she bargain-hunting too long will not stay.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <pb n="5" facs="page_image5"/>
            <pb n="6" facs="page_image6"/>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag7" ana="G">
               <head>G</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>A DREADFUL time this poor Giraffe had with the Grippe last spring!</l>
                  <l>It settled in his throat - just think! Three feet of it! poor thing!</l>
                  <l>He had a smart Gorilla nurse, that knew just what to do,</l>
                  <l>Or else I hardly think he would have managed to pull through.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag8" ana="H">
               <head>H</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>I LIKE you all except your name," the pert Hyena said; </l>
                  <l>"Hippo—Hippo—Bother! I can't keep it in my head!"</l>
                  <l>"Well, let it go at Hippo, then, the larger beast replied; </l>
                  <l>"I shall not take offence at you : I have no silly pride."</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag9" ana="IJ">
               <head>I</head>
               <head>J</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>I J</l>
                  <l>THESE Pyramids," the Ibex said, "are ancient works of men.</l>
                  <l>Can you tell me, Brother Jackal, who erected them, and when?"</l>
                  <l>The Jackal kept on reading, and pretended not to hear;</l>
                  <l>He didn't know, and didn't wish his ignorance to appear.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <pb n="7" facs="page_image7"/>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag10" ana="K">
               <lg>
                  <head>K</head>
                  <l>WHY, bless me!" said a Kangaroo, out walking with his wife;</l>
                  <l>"I never saw so queer a bird before in all my life!"</l>
                  <l>It was a Kiwi-kiwi (or Apteryx if you will);</l>
                  <l>It hasn't got a wing at all, but - mercy!—what a bill!</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag11" ana="L">
               <lg>
                  <head>L</head>
                  <l>I'LL teach you," said the Lion "not to call an officer 'Cop!'</l>
                  <l>Such insolence from loafers, I declare, has got to stop!</l>
                  <l>What will become of Order, and what I will become of Law,</l>
                  <l>If I am not regarded with the right amount of awe?"</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag12" ana="M">
               <lg>
                  <head>M</head>
                  <l>No creature more ungrateful than this Mouse, I'm sure, could be! </l>
                  <l>When from the trap the Monkey and the Magpie</l>
                  <l>He bit the Monkey, till with paii</l>
                  <l>nearly double,— Now, was not that a</l>
                  <l>nice return for helping him in trouble ?</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <pb n="8" facs="page_image8"/>
            <pb n="9" facs="page_image9"/>
            <pb n="10" facs="page_image10"/>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag13" ana="N">
               <head>N</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>LTHOUGH the Newts as dancers have no grace or skill at all, </l>
                  <l>They strangely took a notion that they ought to have a ball.</l>
                  <l>Of course they all imagined that they made a splendid show;</l>
                  <l>But if they were not funny, then I would not tell you so!</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag14" ana="O">
               <head>O</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>'THAT the Owl is full of wisdom, we so frequently have heard, </l>
                  <l>We are likely to suppose that it's an always solemn bird ;</l>
                  <l>But you see it's not unwilling to unbend,</l>
                  <l>And lay aside its dignity, to frolic with a friend.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag15" ana="P">
               <head>P</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>WHAT the Porcupine and Pelican are up to, I can't say; </l>
                  <l>But we safely may assume, I think, it's only friendly play. </l>
                  <l>If the Porcupine should spread his quills while in the other's pouch,</l>
                  <l>not at all unlikely would be a cry of " Ouch!"</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <pb n="11" facs="page_image11"/>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag16" ana="Q">
               <head>Q</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>THANK Fortune! " said the Quagga, " I, at last, have hit a bird. </l>
                  <l>My luck has been just dreadful,— really dreadful, 'pon my word ! </l>
                  <l>I fired off every cartridge, and miss, and riiiss, and miss! </l>
                  <l>d go home empty, if I had not potted this."</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag17" ana="R">
               <head>R</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>the Rhi: An unoffending party that you happen, sir, to meet!</l>
                  <l>You need a little, toning down; you're plainly quite too gay:'</l>
                  <l>And, oh, that Ram he did tone down ; and served him right,</l>
                  <l>I say 1</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag18" ana="S">
               <head>S</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>A STORK was one day painting, as he thought, with great success;</l>
                  <l>But a Squirrel dared the contrary to express. </l>
                  <l>At climbing trees and such things," said the Stork, "you may be smart; </l>
                  <l>"But you simply show your ignorance when you try to talk of Art!'</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <pb n="12" facs="page_image12"/>
            <div>
               <lg>
                  <l>MR. LION imagines he makes a good nurse,</l>
                  <l>But I really don't think you could find a much worse.</l>
                  <l>Not a thing does he do his poor babe to amuse, </l>
                  <l>But sits rocking, and smoking, and reading the news.</l>
                  <l>Mrs. Lion should scold, and oblige him to try</l>
                  <l>To keep baby quiet, and not let him cry.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>SIR Rowley De Powley's a gallant young Frog,</l>
                  <l>Who has journeyed this morning from Greenwater Bog, </l>
                  <l>To pay his addresses to fair Mrs.Mouse.</l>
                  <l>With his friend, Mr. Rat, he's arrived at her house,</l>
                  <l>And it's plain, from his bearing, he doesn't expect</l>
                  <l>That the lovely adored one his suit will reject.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <pb n="13" facs="page_image13"/>
            <pb n="14" facs="page_image14"/>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag19" ana="TU">
               <head>T</head>
               <head>U</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>ARE you well, sir?" asked the Tortoise, as politely as he could.</l>
                  <l>"My health," replied the Turkey, " would, I have no doubt, be good,</l>
                  <l>If 'twere not that Thanksgiving Day so shortly will be here:</l>
                  <l>We Turkeys can't feel gay, you know, with that dread time so near!"</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag20" ana="V">
               <head>V</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>THE Vampire and the Vulture had, one day, a little spat;</l>
                  <l>The Vampire shouted "Baldy!" at the Vulture, - think of that</l>
                  <l>You dubious, mongrel the Vulture in reply, " I scorn you ; </l>
                  <l>for you're but a beast, though like a bird you fly !</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag21" ana="W">
               <head>W</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>A WOLF there was who had, -along with other curious whims,</l>
                  <l>A most surprising mania fior singing psalms and hymns.</l>
                  <l>To many smaller animals he gave instruction free,— </l>
                  <l>A very worthy fellow, (for a Wolf), indeed, was he</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <pb n="15" facs="page_image15"/>
         </div>
         <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag22" ana="X">
            <head>X</head>
            <lg>
               <l>NOT many are the " creatures that with X their names begin:</l>
               <l>To find one we must search amongst the tribes that wear the fin.</l>
               <l>The Xiphias has a long, sharp nose, quite like a sword, you see: </l>
               <l>I think I'd hardly wish to have him point it thus at me.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag23" ana="Y">
            <head>Y</head>
            <lg>
               <l>THE Yamma and the Yak rehearsing for the stage</l>
               <l>For Amateur Theatricals they both have caught the rage;</l>
               <l>They like the plays that treat of love, and think that they can render</l>
               <l>The parts of two fond lovers, in a style most sweet and tender</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <div type="alpha-group" xml:id="ag24" ana="Z">
            <head>Z</head>
            <lg>
               <l>THE Zebra is the animal that's last upon the list;</l>
               <l>He's pictured, to amuse En-to-mol-o-gist. </l>
               <l>This big word.: is the name, you know, bestowed on one who tries</l>
               <l>To find out all about such things bugs and butterflies.</l>
            </lg>
         </div>
         <pb n="16" facs="page_image16"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
